Guide to the Arabic movie posters, 1957-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Arabic movie posters 1957-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
1.5 Linear Feet Approx. 50 Items
The Arabic Film Posters collection comprises more than forty color movie posters published between 1957 and 2008 in Egypt. The posters publicize popular film productions by major Egyptian film directors that were shown in Arab countries. Film genres represented are drama, comedy, adventure, historical fiction and war. The information in each entry is transcribed from the poster, and may include actors, producer, title in Arabic and in English, date released or date of poster publication, and country of origin. Title transcriptions and English translations supplied by library staff. A few of the posters are undated and some have not been positively identified. Smaller posters are housed in an oversize box and the larger sizes in two oversize folders; the smaller posters are currently undescribed but are open to access.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Arabic movie posters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008 and 2009.
Collection Overview
The Arabic Film Posters collection comprises more than forty color movie posters published between 1957 and 2008 in Egypt. The posters publicize popular film productions by major Egyptian film directors that were shown in Arab countries. Film genres represented are drama, comedy, adventure, historical fiction and war. The information in each entry is transcribed from the poster, and may include actors, producer, title in Arabic and in English, date released or date of poster publication, and country of origin. Title transcriptions and English translations supplied by library staff. A few of the posters are undated and some have not been positively identified. Smaller posters are housed in an oversize box and the larger sizes in two oversize folders; the smaller posters are currently undescribed but are open to access.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Motion picture industry -- Egypt
Motion pictures -- Arab countries -- History
Motion pictures -- Social aspects
Posters
Contents of Collection
- Arabic movie posters collection, 1957-2008 and undated, (1 box, 2 oversize folders)
  - Boushkash, Ahmed Yousry, 2008 Jul. 22 (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Hena Maysara (In Better Times), Khaled Yousef, 2007 (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Amam Elfata Eltayesh, Sameh Abdelaziz, 2007 Jun. 20 (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Amalyat Khasa (Private Missions), undated, Othman Abu Laban (Folder 1)
  - Leilet El-Baby Doll (The Baby Doll Night) Adel Adeeb, 2008 May 28 (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Hoosh Elly Weke Menak (Mind What You've Dropped), Ahmed El Guindi, 2007 Aug. 1 (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Khareg Ala El Kanoun (Outlaw), Ahmed Galal, 2007 (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Kamb (Camp), undated, Abdel-Aziz Hashad (Folder 1)
  - Hassan wa Morcus (Hassan and Marcos), 2008 Aug. 1, (Egypt) (Folder 1)
  - Khaleej Neama (Neama Bay), Majdy Al Hawary, 2008 (Folder 1)
  - Halo Amrika (Hello America), Nader Galal, 2000 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Al Tawous (The Peacock), Kamal El Sheikh, 1982 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Tabbakh Al-Rayyes (The President's Chef), Said Hamid, 2009 [?] (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Zaza (Zaza), Aly Abdel Khalek, undated, Egypt (Folder 2)
  - Forsan Akher Zaman (Knights of Medhat El-Sibai, 1992 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Hata La Yatir Al-Dokhan (As not to Fly the Smoke), Ahmen Yehia, 1984 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Essabet El Dr. Omar (Dr. Omar's Gang), Ali Edreess, undated (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Sheeka Mara [?] undated, [Probable movie title] (Folder 2)
  - Ahlam Hakekya (Real Dreams), Mohammed Gomaa, 2007 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Nos Sa'a Gawaz (Half an Hour of Marriage), Fatin Abdel Wahab, 1969(Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - El Jassus (The Spy), Niazi Mostafa, 1965 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Nisa Da'iat, (Lost Women), Houssam Ed-Din Mostafa, 1975 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Hena Maysara (In Better Times), Khaled Yousef, 2007 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - An El Ashq Wel Hawa (Kamla Abu Zekry), 2006 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - El Azab El Talata (The Three Bachelors), Mahmoud Farid, 1964 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - La Tabki.. Ya Habib El-Omr (Do Not Cry, O Life's Love), Ahmad Yahya, 1979 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Baat Hayasti (Sold My Life), Mohammad Aslan, undated, (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Al-Fatawa (The Tough), Salah Abouseif, 1957 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Ahmad Yahya Farid Shawki [?] [Title could not positively be identified], undated. (Folder 2)
  - L'anaat Imra'ah (Woman's Curse), Niazi Mostafa, 1974 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Wa Maada Kitar Aloumr (And Life Passed), Atef Salem, 1975 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Ihna illa Saraqna Al-Haramiyyah, Medhat Al-Sibai, 1989 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - [Shaytan Al-Bosfor?] The King of Bosphorus, Niazi Mostafa. 1972 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Al-Bousa (The Kiss), Atef Salem, 1978 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Osman Al-Jabbar, undated [Probable movie title] (Folder 2)
  - Dala'al Al-Banat (Spoiled Girls), Hassan Al-Saifi, 1969 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Siddiq Al-Wafa (My Faithful Friend), Fazel Saleh, undated (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - Bord Sa'id (Port Said), Ezzel Din Zulfikar, 1957 (Egypt) (Folder 2)
  - A'ntriya'r: Wa Al-Saharay [?], undated [Probable movie title] (Folder 2)
  - Additional Arabic movie posters (approx. 20), smaller sizes (Box 1)